Thanks for packing me lunch, Sis. You could make this a habit.
珍しく弁当を作ってくれたのはありがたいが 姉貴よ
This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance to real persons, groups or events is purely coincidental.
なぜエスニックが
But why the weird ethnic food?
Oreki! Thanks for looking after the stand!
折木さん
店番ご苦労さまです
Sure.
We won, man!
勝った勝った
It was a close call though.
際どかったけどね
Congratulations.
優勝おめでとう
Thank you! We couldn't have done it without you, Oreki!
ありがとうございます
折木さんのお力添えのお陰です
No... Oh well.
いや まあ
But I never would've thought you'd do something like that.
でも驚いたよ
奉太郎はああいうことをする地球人類で最後の一人だと思ってたのに
In fact, you're the last person on Earth I'd expect that from.
The whole festival atmosphere got to me.
祭りの空気に当てられただけだ もうやらん
Never again.
That reminds me, Oreki.
それでですね 折木さん
There's something I'd like you to see.
見ていただきたいものがあるんですが
The cooking club has lost their ladle.
Juumonji
Look at this.
The cooking club has lost their ladle.
Juumonji
これです
The cooking club has lost their ladle.
Juumonji
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
KamiGami
Today is a real mess, but I get over it with a sigh
複雑に構えた今日が 息を呑んで澄ましてる
You get the idea, right?
身に覚えあるだろう 君はどうしたい
What do you wanna do?
You act as if nothing happened
何もなかったそぶりで  かばう痛みはもう
As if your heart didn't ache
It almost feels encouraging,
心強いくらいに 急かすんだ
the way you're rushing me
Hold it and let it overflow
掴んでこぼして 不完全な僕たちが
We're all imperfect
光って見えない 未来の自分を創れるなら
I can't see it well in the light,
but if we can change our future selves
Wake up and run
目覚めるまま走れ 蜃気楼を追い越して
Go and surpass the mirage
Try to change and run
変わりたいまま走れ 自由な違和感で
with the discomfort of freedom
届きそうな輝きと今を選んでいこう
We can reach that shining light
Follow it into the present
Don't hesitate to act
飛びたつ手を知らない
Deep or quick, just keep breathing
深い 浅い 呼吸を重ねて
Hyouka
十文字事件
The Juumonji Incident
So your ladle got stolen?
お玉が盗まれてたのか
うん 私たちのとこだけ
Yeah. And only ours.
Somone must have lot of free time.
暇な奴がいたんだなあ
And it's not just the Cooking Club!
お料理研だけじゃないんだ
It happened to the Go Club and the A Capella Choir as well!
ほかに囲碁部もアカペラ部も同じ目に遭ったみたい
And the Fortune Teller Club! They got a note just like that!
占い研もです
これと同じ文面で
A claim of responsibility...
ええと 犯行声明
Someone must have an awful lot of free time.
物凄く暇な奴がいたんだな
うん このスパイスの香りがまた
And this spice smells just...
Oreki!
折木さん
まずい これは駄目だ
This is bad!
Real bad!
It's coming...
いつものあれが 千反田愛瑠の好奇心が
Chitanda Eru's curiosity...
is going up in flames!
発動する
Who would do this during the culture fair, of all times?
文化祭に乗じてこんなことをするのは誰なのか
なぜ十文字さんの名前を騙るのか
Why would they use the Juumonji family name?
Why would they steal one item after another?
どうして次々に盗むのか
I can't stop think—
私 気になりまー
We don't have time for that.
そんなことをしてる場合じゃない
The anthology—
この文集が
Yeah, the anthology!
その文集のこと 何だけどね
Even though we're promoting it at events,
地味にイベントで宣伝したりしてもやっぱりたいして売れないと思うんだ
it's not exactly flying off the shelves.
Yeah, we should do something more flashy.
たしかに 何かもっと派手なことをやらないと駄目よね
Yes, exactly!
そう それでだ
Why don't we sell this mystery to the News Poster Club?
この怪盗事件を壁新聞部に売り込むのはどうかな
It'd be great if we could get some time on the school radio tomorrow too.
できれば明日の校内ラジオの出演も頂く
With that kind of publicity, even this anthology would sell!
そこまで行けば この文集も相当捌けるんじゃないかな
I see!
なるほど
That's a good idea!
それはいい考えですね
And what did you plan to tell them?
売り込むんだって どう売り込む
That incident has nothing to do with the Classics Club.
古典部とは関係ない事件だぞ
How about this...
こんな感じさ
The Classics Club's super sleuth, Oreki Houtarou,
古典部の名探偵 折木奉太郎
has caught the thief sowing discord throughout the culture fair behind the Juumonji name!
文化祭を騒がす怪盗十文字を捕える
Read all about this and his other great achievements,
これまでの彼の活躍は
古典部の文集「氷菓」をご覧ぜよ
exclusively in the Classics Club anthology, Hyouka!
That's a wonderful idea!
それは素晴らしい方法です
Not bad.
まあ 悪くはないわね
I know, right!
でしょう これなら十文字の正体も暴けるし
This way we can expose Juumonji
and promote the Classics Club at the same—
古典部の宣伝にも
Give me a break!
ふざけるな
"Super sleuth," my ass!
何が名探偵だ
I won't be your mascot panda!
客寄せパンダなぞ 絶対やらんぞ
Let's at least try, Oreki.
頑張ってみましょうよ 折木さん
Even if I were willing to dance to your little tune,
仮にピエロになるとしてもだ
the student body alone makes a thousand subjects,
生徒だけで千人
and that's not even counting the outsiders!
一般客を入れれば それ以上入るんだぞ
How do you expect me to find the culprit in that crowd?
その中からどうやって捕まえろって言うんだ
Would it be that difficult?
難しい ですか
It's impossible.
無理だ
If only the thief would target the Classics Club...
その怪盗もどきが 古典部をターゲットにしてくれればなあ
Well...
まあ な
Then let's stage—
なら 自作自演で
No thanks!
却下
いたっ
じ 冗談だよ 冗談
I'm kidding, I'm kidding!
Target us, huh?
ターゲットか
Which clubs got hit so far?
これまでどこの部活が盗られた
The Go Club, the A Capella Choir, the Cooking Club,
囲碁部 アカペラ部 お料理研と
ええと 何だっけ
and who else?
The Fortune Teller Club!
占い研です
Yeah, that!
そうそう
A Capella... Go... Fortune Teller...
アカペラ部 囲碁部 占い研 お料理研か
Cooking Club...
ABC!
「ABC」
もしもし 鈴木君
Hello, Suzuki?
The clubs whose names start with an "e" sound in Japanese are
「え」のつく部活は映研 園芸部 演劇部 SF部ね
Has anything gone missing from your club?
君のクラブで何か盗まれたのか
the Movie Lab, the Gardening Club, the Acting Troupe, and the SF Club.
Yeah, exactly!
そう 盗難だよ
What do you mean?
どういうことですか
ないんだ じゃあな
I was afraid you'd say that.
It's a pattern, and a pretty simple one at that.
法則性だよ それも極め付けに簡単な奴
A Capella Choir. Go Club. Fortune Teller Club.
アカペラ部 囲碁部 占い研
Then there's a missing letter, then we have the Cooking Club.
一文字飛んでるが お料理研
So if a club starting with the "e" sound shows up, we'll know for sure.
これで「え」が出てくれば間違いない
They're in Japanese alphabetical order, right?
五十音順ですね
水鉄砲 ああ うん ありがとう
Correct.
Yeah, thanks!
そういうことだ
Gotou
In call
Ending call...
Gotou
Call ended
園芸部がやられてる
The Gardening Club got hit.
They took their eyes off it for one moment and one of their water guns was missing..
ちょっと留守にした間に 水鉄砲盗られたって
A water gun?
水鉄砲
To put out the fires when frying potatoes.
焼き芋の火の用心だとさ
There was a guy from the Gardening Club yesterday who had it with him.
昨日の客が園芸部部員で持ってた
Wait a moment...
ちょっと待って
In Christie's ABC Murders,
クリスティンの「ABC殺人事件」だと
someone whose name began with 'A' got murdered in a place beginning with 'A', and so on.
「A」のつく土地で「A」のつく人が殺されるのよね
The Cooking Club lost their ladle...
で お料理研からお玉が盗まれた
ああ ちょっと待って
Hold on.
千反田さん 占い研から盗まれたものは聞いてる
Chitanda, do you know what got stolen from the Fortune Teller Club?
Yes! It was the Wheel of Fortune, the tarot card.
はい 運命の輪でした タロットカードの
Okay.
オーケー となると
That means...
A Capella Choir       ->     (drink)
Go Club       ->   (Go stone)
Fortune Teller Club->   (Wheel of Fortune)
Gardening Club  ->    (water gun)
Cooking Club    ->      (ladle)
The Gardening Club's water gun was an AK.
園芸部の水鉄砲は「AK」じゃないか
AK? What's that?
AK 何それ
A Russian assault rifle.
ロシア製の突撃銃だ
And if that works,
そんなのっていいんだったらさ
we could just call the "go stone" a regular "stone" as well.
囲碁部は石じゃない
Probably.
たぶんね
And the A Capella Choir...
じゃ アカペラ部は
It doesn't matter. You just need to figure it out.
何でもいい 調べればすぐ分かる
Why do you say that?
どうしてだい
犯人の署名は何だ
How did the culprit sign their messages?
Juumonji.
十文字なんだけど
Why do you read it like that?
なぜそう読む
If you read it normally, it's "juumoji," or "ten letters"!
普通に読めば十文字だろうが
Ten letters!
Ten letters
十文字
I see! The first ten letters in Japanese are a-i-u-e-o then ka-ki-ku-ke-ko!
そうか あいうえおかきくけこで十文字
Which means the tenth will be...
つまり最後の十文字目は
"Kotenbu"! The Classics Club!
こ 古典部です
I'd say we're involved enough for some publicity, wouldn't you?
こいつは古典部を売り込むのには十分な材料だと思わんか
I'll go and ask the News Poster club right away!
私 早速壁新聞部にかけ売ってきます
Aren't we enthusiastic?
張り切っとるなあ
どうした
What's wrong?
I just realized something.
ちょっと思いついたことがあってね
This incident...
この件は
No, never mind.
いや いいんだ 調べてくる
I'm gonna go investigate some more.
What's gotten into him?
何だ あいつ
Who knows?
さあ
You're not going back to the Manga Lab?
伊原は漫研に帰らないのか
I am.
帰るわよ
なに 私がここにいちゃう 悪いの
What? You got a problem with me being here?
Why are you angry?
なぜ怒る
I'm not!
怒ってないわよ
Biology
Prep Room
The basics of negotiation...
交渉のコツ
Firstly, make the other party believe you expect great things of them.
一つ 相手に期待しているように見せること
Secondly, downplay what you have to gain.
二つ こちらの利益を小さく見せること
And lastly, ask a boy in private.
三つ 人目につかない所で異性に頼むこと
Okay!
よし
Roger! I'll go interview the Gardening Club!
避け 園芸部にインタビューしてくるー
What about the A Capella Choir?
おい アカペラ部はどうだった
I'm calling them now!
今電話してる
And the Cooking Club?
お料理研だ 何してる
速くしろよ
Hurry up!
Yeah, exactly!
そうだよ 何度言ったら分かる
How many times do I need to tell you?!
あの あの
Don't ask questions, act!
喋っとる暇があったら動け
Sorry, Chitanda, we're kinda busy.
すまんない 千反田さん
今ちょっと立て込んでるんだ また後で来てくれないかな
Could you come back later?
Sure, then I'll...
はい ではまた後
Sorry, I can't do that!
じゃ駄目です
It's about the Classics Club!
古典部のことなんです
その話なら 特別なネタがなきゃ駄目
Sorry, but we can't cover you unless you've got a story.
I've got one!
そのネタがあるんです
And what would that be?
と いうと
I don't really have time. Could you hur—
あまり時間がないんだ 手短
ちょっ おい どこ行く気だ
Where are you taking me?
This is something I can only tell the News Poster Club about.
このことは壁新聞部にしかご相談できないことなのです
I... you know...
つまり その
I expect great things of you!
私 期待してます
そ そう ありがとう
Oh...
Thanks.
But the Classics Club would hardly gain anything...
でも古典部の利益は小さいのです
I see.
What do you say?
どうですか 何か頑張ろうって気になりませんか
Don't you think we should at least try?
いや 意味分かんないんだけど
I don't really see what you're getting at.
ですよね
I thought so.
Like I said, we're full up already.
言っただろ 立て込んでるって
If you don't have a story, I'll catch you later.
ネタがないなら あとあと
ま 待ってください
Please wait!
I've got a story!
そう ネタです
Someone's stealing things all over the culture fair!
文化祭でいろんなクラブから物を盗んでる人がいるんです
The culprit is—
その犯人が
Juumonji! Juumonji, right?
十文字 十文字のことだろ
Do you know something?!
何が知ってるのか
Uh... I...
あの その
なるほど 五十音順か
I see.
Japanese alphabetical order.
The Fortune Teller Club got hit too, huh?
占い研もやられてたとは それでか
That's why...
That's why what?
それでっとは
ここ壁新聞部だろ
The News Poster Club starts with a "ka" sound in Japanese, right?
That means you're—
ということは
We lost our cutter knife.
カッターナイフをやられた
今お忙しそうなのはそのことなんですか
That's why everything seemed so hectic?
Yeah. It's kind of a pain, but this is exactly the kind of story we were looking for.
うん 悔しいのもあるけど
こういうネタを待ってたんだ
I'm impressed you figured it out.
それにしても よく気付いたね
It was Oreki.
はい 折木さんが
ああ そう
I see.
とにかく ありがとう 助かったよ
Anyway, thanks for the help.
Tougaito, please wait!
遠垣内さん 待ってください
I gave you your story,
ここまで教えたんですから
so please write about the Classics Club too!
古典部のこともちゃんと書いてください
Okay? Please!
いいですね お願いします
But if I carried on like that, I'd basically be saying I didn't trust him.
あそこで念を押すなんて遠垣内さんを疑うのと同じです
Sor—
ごめん
すみま
Chitanda!
千反田さん
How was it?
どう 成果はあった
Did you succeed?
Well...
まあ どうなんでしょう
I'm not sure.
Never mind. Just talking to myself.
すみません こちらの話です
Oh.
そう
Anyway, I asked the A Capella Choir!
それより アカペラ部から聞いたんだ
They had a box of apple juice stolen!
盗まれたのはアップルジュースだったって
I heard the News Poster Club got their cutter knife stolen.
私も壁新聞部で聞きました
カッターナイフが盗まれたそうです
That's "ka" for you. It's definitely Japanese alphabetical order.
「か」だね 五十音順は確定だ
Next up is "ki", and the only one starting with that sound is the Magic Club.
こうなると次の「き」は奇術部しかない
Their next performance is coming up.
奇術部の次の公演はもうすぐだ
If we watch it carefully...
これに張り込めば
You want to stake out the location?
現場を押えるんですか
Yeah.
うん その手の怪盗の弱点だね
That's the thief's weakness.
They're bound by their own rules.
自分のルールに縛られてしまう
And therefore, they shouldn't be too hard to catch.
十文字の正体を見破るのも難しくない
But if you catch him at "ki"...
でも「き」で見破っちゃったら
Then he won't make it to us?
犯人が古典部までたどり着けないっていうんだろ
Don't worry, we'll work something out.
それぐらい いくらでも手は打てるさ
I guess, but still...
そうかもしれませんけど
Anyway, I'm off to stake out a magic show.
とにかく奇術部に張り込んでみるよ
Let's hope we're not late.
ぜんは急げだ それじゃ
Later!
秋分
阴阳相半也
Autumn Equinox
When light and dark are in balance.
Hyouka
Program
Prelude
Living Dead
Takamura Youichi, first-year
Rainbow Chain
Nagai Kaori, first-year
Ubiquity
Tayama Kazuya, second-year
Close-up Card Magic
Takamura Youichi and Nagai Kaori, first-years
Bowl and Jewel
Tayama Kazuya, second-year
Finale
First Performance
Fifth Performance
It's only 2pm.
まだ二時か
Well, if it isn't Fuku!
福部じゃないか
Hey, Tani.
や 谷君
If you're here, then I guess you know about it too, huh?
ここに来てるってことは 知ってるのか
What?
何を
Don't play dumb with me!
恍けんなよ 怪盗十文字のことさ
You're here for the Juumoji thief!
Yeah.
まあね
Then this shall be our next clash of wits!
じゃあ これが次の勝負だな
Did you hear about the News Poster Club?
壁新聞部のことは？
They lost their cutter knife. I know.
カッターナイフだろ 知ってるよ
The News Poster guys have got their heads in the game.
壁新聞部の連中 ゲームに乗ったぞ
Their next issue will be headlined by the Juumoji incident.
次号のトップは十文字の記事だ
And whoever catches the thief
しかも怪盗をとられた団体には号外を丸ごと提供するつもりらしい
gets a whole special issue about their club!
Sorry, but I'll be winning this.
まあ 悪いが こいつは俺の勝ちだよ
You might not realize it at first, but I'm a huge mystery fan!
こう見えても 実はミステリーファンなんだ
Please be gentle.
お手柔らかにね
Earth Sci. Prep. room
伊原 お前クリスティのABC殺人事件は読んでるよな
Ibara, you've read Christie's ABC Murders, right?
Of course.
あたりまえでしょ
Then I have a question.
なら聞きたいんだが ABCの順に殺す理由は何かあったのか
Was there any reason the murders took place in alphabetical order?
If I told you that, it'd spoil the whole story.
ネタバレだけど いいの
I don't mind.
頼む
You're wondering what kind of lame story would have the murderer kill alphabetically
ABCの順に殺したかったから そうしてみました
just 'cause they felt like it, right?
なんてお話になると思う？
And I bet you feel the same way about this case as well.
この件も同じか考えてるわけ？
Yeah.
そうだな
Anyone could've figured out it was Japanese alphabetical order.
五十音順の法則はいずれ誰にでも分かることだった
This Juumoji guy must've known that too.
それは十文字だって予想しているはずだ
Guess you're right.
確かにそうね
So I was wondering whether there was any deeper meaning or intention behind these thefts.
この盗み方に何か別の意図や意味が隠されている可能性を考えていた
まあ ただの愉快犯でなければだが
Unless he's just doing it for fun.
Oreki...
折木 あんた十文字を捕まえたいと思ってるの？
You want to catch Juumoji, don't you?
俺が？ なぜ
Why would I?
You're so eager.
熱心だから
I couldn't care less.
俺はどうでもいいさ
But if Chitanda's gonna get stuck into it, I can't exactly avoid it either.
だが千反田が気になると言った以上
最後には避けられない問題になる
You could just ignore her.
無視すればいいじゃない
She's not the kind you can just ignore. That's why it's such a pain.
それが出来る相手じゃないから面倒なんだろうが
ばか
You dweeb.
And that's that.
さてと
You're going?
行くのか
Yeah.
うん あ そういえば 小麦粉ありがとうね
Thanks for the flour, by the way.
It was a real help.
助かったわ
おお それそれ
Oh, right!
You want me to pay you?
あんた お金とる気
That hurts, you know.
人聞きの悪い
I traded that flour, just like in One Red Paperclip.
あの小麦粉 わらしべプロトコルで手に入れたものなんだ
What's that?
何それ
Give me something in exchange.
代わりに何かくれ
Though I guess we could just end it here.
なければプロトコル終了でもいいが
I see... Fair enough.
なるほど そうね
You can have this.
これあげる
You sure?
いいのか
うん
But...
でも それがないと
Without that, your cosp—
コスプレ… に
コスプレって言うな！ ばか！
Don't call it that, stupid!
It's almost time for the Magic Club's fifth performance!
奇術部第五回公演 間もなく始まりまーす
Good afternoon, Irisu.
入須先輩 こんにちは
Oh, it's you.
あ 君か
Do you like magic tricks?
お好きなんですか 手品
"Like" might be too strong a word, but...
好きというほど詳しくないが 変か
Why? Is it weird?
No, just a bit unexpected.
いえ ちょっと意外で
Don't tell me...
もしかして
Yeah, right.
まさかね
You don't have to put it like that, though.
でもさ 何もあんな言い方しなくてもいいんじゃない
That's Mayaka's senior.
摩耶花の先輩か 昨日漫研で見かけたな
I saw her yesterday at the Manga Lab.
This looks fun!
面白そう
Hey, look!
ねえ ちょっと あれ
勝手に決めないで
Whoa, and here's Tanabe with none other than
おっと 田名辺先輩と これは敬礼
まあまあ そう怒こんなって
His Highness the student council president, Kurayama Muneyoshi himself.
生徒会長陸山宗芳閣下だ
Hey, Empress.
や 女帝さん
Hello.
どうも
Hey.
Ah, Fukube.
おお 福部
Sir!
どうも
Thank you for your patience!
お待たせしました
The Magic Club's performance will now begin!
奇術部公演 これより開演します
本日はお集まりいただき 誠にありがとうございます
Thank you very much for coming today!
Without further ado, please enjoy the fruits of our labor,
我々奇術部一同が日々磨いて参りました芸をとことご覧ください
as we perform for you the art of magic!
Showtime.
さて これだけの衆人監視の中
But how does the thief known only as Juumoji plan to strike before so many watchful eyes?
どうやって盗みを働くんだい
怪盗十文字
Now then, Takamura Youichi's Living De—
では 早速高村洋一演じるリビングデッドから…
どうした
What is it?
Um...
その
あ キャンドル！
A candle!
すいません
Sorry!
Dammit!
くそ
When was it?
いつだ いつもなにも
No, that's not it!
No one went near the stage except the performers!
演者以外はスデージには誰も近付いてない
Which means...
ということは 最初から盗られていた？
it was missing from the beginning?
What am I even doing here?
何のために僕はここで
Now that I think about it,
考えてみれば
no one said Juumoji would steal it during the performance!
十文字が公演中に盗む保障なんてどこにもなかった
Welcome to the
Manga Lab!
ありがとうございました
Sales seem to have picked up since yesterday.
昨日より売れてるかな
Yeah, they have!
うん 売れてる ポスターの効き目かも
It's probably thanks to the posters.
I'm glad.
よかった
You should've just listened to your elders in the first place.
やっぱり先輩の言うとおりにしてたらよかったんじゃない
We would've sold more yesterday if a certain someone hadn't been in the way.
ねえ 誰かさんが変に反対しなきゃ
昨日だってもっと売れてたのにね
Aww, give her a break. I'm almost feeling pity here.
まあまあ そんなに言ったらかわいそうだよ
Don't worry about it.
気にすることないよ
うん
I know.
Seriously, you couldn't find it?
大体さ 見付かんなかったとか
I bet she made the whole thing up.
あれ 嘘でしょう
She just got scared of showing us some crappy manga.
実はたいしたことない漫画を見せるのが急に怖くなったんじゃないの
She tried to win the argument by naming some obscure indie title nobody's ever heard of.
聞いたこともない同人出して つぶってみたかっただけでしょ
Totally!
いるいる
As if there'd even be a manga like that in the first place!
どうせそんな漫画あるわけないんだから
Hey!
ちょっと！
ストップ
Stop!
That's the end of it.
そこまでね
If you haven't heard of it, keep your mouth shut.
聞いたこともないなら黙ってること
We're back.
ただいま
B-But...
で でも先輩
Weren't you listening?
聞こえなかった？
I said if you haven't heard of it, shut your trap.
知らないなら黙ってろって言ったのよ
Oh, President, how was the Magic Club?
あ 部長 奇術部どうでした？
It was fun.
うん 楽しかったわよ
へえ 私も明日見に行こうかな
I thought I might stop by tomorrow.
Yeah, check it out!
うん 行っておいでよ
When was it again?
何時からでしたっけ
They have lots of shows each day, so you can catch them anytime.
一日に何回かやってるから 大丈夫だと思うよ
I see. Then—
そっか それじゃ…
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
ごめん ちょっと出てくるね
Gotcha!
うん わかった
Fuk—
福…
I'm pathetic.
情けないな
Running off to Fuku and the others.
福ちゃんたちに逃げたくなってる
Ibara!
伊原
あ はい 湯浅先輩
Ah, Yuasa.
I'm sorry it had to end up like this.
ごめんね 変なことになっちゃって
Why are you apologizing?
どうして先輩が謝るんですか
Because I didn't say anything, even though I wanted to take your side.
ずっと黙ってたから
伊原の味方してあげたかったんだけど
But if you did, it'd turn into all-out war between you and Kouchi!
でも そうしたら 河内先輩と湯浅先輩の対立になっちゃいますよね
I don't want that... This is fine.
私 そんなの嫌ですから
これでいいと思います
I don't think Ayako really meant it.
亜也子はね 本気じゃないのよ
Ayako?
亜也子？
Kouchi.
河内のこと
Kouchi Ayako.
河内亜也子
What do you mean, she didn't mean it?
本気じゃないって どうしてそんなこと分かるんですか
Because she and I are friends.
亜也子と私 友達だから
That's all?
それだけで
Ayako and Haruna were friends too.
亜也子と春菜も友達だったの
Haruna? Who's that?
春菜 誰ですか
Anjou Haruna. Co-author of Dead at Dusk.
安城春菜
「夕べには骸に」の作者の一人よ
You mean it was a collaboration?
合作だったんですか
Someone else drew it. Ayako might know who.
作画は他の誰か 亜也子なら知ってるかもしれないけど
Do you know what year and class they're in?
その人 何年何組みですか
Haruna doesn't go to this school anymore.
あ 春菜はもういないよ 転校しちゃった
She transferred.
I see...
そうですか
But how do you know she didn't mean it,
でも その安城春菜さんと友達だからって
just because she was friends with Anjou Haruna?
なぜ河内先輩が本気じゃなかったって言えるんですか
Well... That's a good question.
そうだよね ごめん
But I can't explain it any further.
でも これ以上は説明できないな
Ayako's my friend after all.
だって 亜也子は友達だから
Are you worried the explanation would make her look bad?
説明すると河内先輩の悪口になるんですか
Give me a minute to cool down.
少し涼んだら戻ります
Ibara...
伊原
I'll be back right away.
すぐに戻りますから
Hyouka
Extra! Extra! Read all about it!
号外号外 必見だよ
Hyouka
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Special
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Kamiyama
High
Monthly
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Who's the next target?
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Phantom Thief!
The
Juumoji
incident!
Not to mention that this outrageous fellow dared to strike us, the News Poster Club, and stole our cutter knife
from right under our noses! Can you believe it? This is a clear and obvious challenge against the press!
And that is all the information we were able to gather thus far. From this, our dear readers, we conclude that Juumoji will
strike for the last time between 12 and 2 pm on the third day, targeting either the Classics Club or the Artisan Workshop.
Classics Club
Tougaito!
遠垣内さん
They won, Houtarou.
やられたよ 奉太郎
A candle was stolen from the Magic Club.
奇術部からキャンドルが盗まれてた
There was a note claiming responsibility, as always.
犯行声明も見つかったよ
Isn't that for the best?
よかったじゃないか 古典部に来るまで十文字には捕まってほしくない
We don't want to catch Juumoji before they target us, after all.
まあ そうなんだけどさ
That's true, but...
I thought I'd be able to catch them in the act.
現場を押さえられるかと思って
You thought they'd strike during the performance?
公演中に盗難が起きると？
Yeah.
うん
Juumoji never announced when it was going to happen.
十文字が犯行時刻まで決めてなかっただろ
The Cooking Club's ladle also went missing beforehand, didn't it?
お料理研のお玉だって そうだったはずだぞ
If you realized that, you could've said something.
気付いてたなら教えてくれよ
I didn't know you were planning to stake out a magic show.
お前が現場を押さえるつもりだったなんて知らなかった
まあ そうだけど
That's true.
I'm back!
戻りました
Irisu said that the 20 copies I left with her are selling well!
入須さんにお預けした二十部の氷菓ですが
売れ行き好調だそうです
She's the one handling it, after all.
まあ あの入須のやることだからな
And one more thing.
それと もう一つです
The News Poster Club's 4pm issue featured the Juumoji incident.
壁新聞の午後四時号に十文字事件のことが取り上げられていました
They wrote about how the thefts were in Japanese alphabetical order.
五十音順の法則もしっかり載ってます
The Classics Club was mentioned too.
古典部の名前も出てましたよ
Juumoji's last target will be either the Artisan Workshop or us.
十文字さんの最後の犯行は古典部 若しくは工作部だって
There's an Artisan Workshop too?
工作部？ そんなのあったのか
There is, now that you mention it.
あったね そういえば
If they get hit instead of us, our whole plan is ruined.
そっちに行かれたら計画はご破算だね
I thought I might talk to the Radio Club tomorrow.
明日は放送部に交渉に行こうと思ってます
Hopefully we can get the Classics Club mentioned during their broadcast.
校内放送で古典部のことを取り上げてもらえれば
What's wrong?
何ですか
Nothing.
いや お前 疲れて…
You just look a bit tir—
お疲れー
Hey, guys!
Hey, Mayaka!
摩耶花
How many did we sell today?
今日の売り上げはどう？
16, if you don't count the 20 we gave to Irisu.
入須に渡した二十部を除けば 十六部だ
Excellent!
快挙だね
Excellent?
快挙
I guess.
そうかもね
137 remaining
It's my job to negotiate with the other clubs, but...
お願いして回るのは私がすべきことですけど
It's so... exhausting...
何だか 疲れました
Body Talk.
ボディトーク
It's not as good as Dead at Dusk, but it's better than nothing.
「夕べには骸に」には一枚落ちるけど
Yeah, this'll do.
やっぱりこれもいい
Mine don't hold a candle to either.
私のは百枚落ちる
Houtarou's changed.
奉太郎は変わった
Or at least, he's showing progress.
いや 真価を発揮した
Ever since he met Chitanda.
千反田さんに出会うことで
He's turning into someone full of those surprises I love so much.
僕がこよなく愛する意外性を秘めた人間として
Am I truly happy about it?
果たして僕はそれをただ「愉快だ」とだけ思っているだろうか
There are over a thousand suspects.
容疑者は千人以上
There's no way anyone could simply deduce the culprit's identity.
この中から推理で犯人を導き出すなんて
どんな人間にも不可能だ
Which means that our only choice is to catch them red-handed.
だとしたら できるのは現行犯逮捕
これだけだ
This incident isn't fit for Houtarou. I'll unveil its truth myself.
奉太郎向きじゃないこの事件の真相を
僕の手で解き明かす
Houtarou,
奉太郎 十文字は僕が捕まえてみせるよ
I'm gonna catch Juumoji!
Mail-order Sales
Oh, they're doing mail-order sales?
Next time: The Final Target.
The Final Target
状況は非科学的に 感情のモンタージュ
誰が誰を呼んでる
振り向けば逃げてく視線（感じる）
気のせいじゃつれないよ アンテナは才能って言うでしょ
だって（だって） 知りたい（君は違うの？）
青春の温度差 今のうち正してあげるよ
明日解決するなら 今でもよくない？
君のミステリー解いてみたい
少年の秘密めいた背中探せ（今日も）
君はファンタジー 惹かれてゆくよ（ずるい）
膨らんだ好奇心 とりたくはないのに
気になるよ 興味深い どうして
次回　最後の標的